Contact

lopezdeprado@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lopezdeprado (LinkedIn)

QuantResearch.org (Personal)

Top Skills

Trading Systems

Market Microstructure

Portfolio Management

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Investment Management Certificate (IMC)

Approved Person for CF26 & CF27 (Trader & Investment Manager)

Member, perfect test score (12/12+36/36, RAPM)

Honors-Awards

Best Doctoral Dissertation

National Award for Academic Excellence

Quant of the Year 2019

Futures & Options Hall of Fame

Publications

Measuring Loss Potential of Hedge Fund Strategies

The Exchange of Flow Toxicity

The Sharpe ratio Efficient Frontier

Mathematics and Economics: A reality check

Pseudo-Mathematics and Financial Charlatanism: The Effects of Backtest Overfitting on Out-Of-Sample Performance

Marcos Lopez de Prado

Founder at TRUE POSITIVE TECHNOLOGIES. Professor of Practice at CORNELL UNIVERSITY

New York

Summary

Over the past 20 years, I have pursued three simultaneous careers, as (a) an investment manager, (b) a professor, and (c) a researcher at a leading U.S. National laboratory. This combination of backgrounds has allowed me to manage multibillion-dollar funds, produce numerous innovations that have resulted in 13 patents (11 of which have been bought by various firms), publish three textbooks used in leading university programs, and a large number of peer-reviewed publications in academic journals. I have helped modernize finance, by popularizing the use of machine learning and supercomputing, and by developing statistical tests that identify false investment strategies (false positives). Since 2017, I have ranked as the most-read author in economics (SSRN). In 2019, I was named the "Quant of the Year" by The Journal of Portfolio Management, and the U.S. Congress invited me to offer testimony on Al policy, and the impact of automation in the financial sector.

Experience

TRUE POSITIVE TECHNOLOGIES, L.P.

Founder

March 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Greater New York City Area

TPT helps bring Asset Management into the Age of Machine Learning

Cornell University

Professor of Practice

2015 - Present (5 years)

Greater New York City Area

I teach Machine Learning at the School of Engineering

LAWRENCE BERKELEY NATIONAL LABORATORY

Research Affiliate

2011 - Present (9 years)

Patents

Method and system for determining a weight allocation in a group comprising a plurality of items

"Systems and Methods for Controlling Electronic Exchange Behaviour based on an Informed Trading Metric"

Systems and Methods for Crowdsourcing of Algorithmic Forecasting

Hierarchical Capital Allocation

Hierarchical Construction of Investment Portfolios Using Clustered Machine Learning

Berkeley, CA

- Scientist at the Computational Research Division.
- Berkeley Lab is a member of the national laboratory system supported by the U.S. Department of Energy through its Office of Science. It is managed by the University of California (UC) and is charged with conducting unclassified research across a wide range of scientific disciplines. Thirteen scientists associated with Berkeley Lab have won the Nobel Prize. Fifty-seven Lab scientists are members of the National Academy of Sciences (NAS).
- http://www.lbl.gov

AQR Capital Management
Principal, Head of Machine Learning
August 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 1 month)
Greenwich, CT

GUGGENHEIM PARTNERS

Senior Managing Director 2014 - 2018 (4 years)

Greater New York City Area

I founded and led Guggenheim Partners' Quantitative Investment Strategies (QIS) business, with the goal of applying cutting-edge machine learning to the development of high-capacity strategies that delivered superior risk-adjusted returns, receiving \$13 billion in assets from institutional investors.

- Press release from Guggenheim Partners (02/06/18): https://goo.gl/utShhN
- Guggenheim Partners has over \$305 billion AUM. All of the affiliated insurance companies gave their largest allocations to my business unit.
- http://www.GuggenheimPartners.com

TUDOR INVESTMENT CORPORATION

Head of Global Quantitative Research 2008 - 2013 (5 years)

- Tudor Investment Corporation manages approx. \$15 billion. Its outstanding track record spans over the last 3 decades. It has been ranked best hedge fund worldwide in Alpha generation by ABSOLUTE RETURN + ALPHA Journal (September 2009).
- http://www.tudorfunds.com

CITADEL INVESTMENT GROUP, LLC Senior Quantitative Researcher

2005 - 2006 (1 year)

Greater Chicago Area

UBS

Head of Quantitative Equity Research 2001 - 2004 (3 years)

Zurich, Switzerland

- Quantitative Research and programming. Development of Statistical models for determining trading opportunities. Portfolio Optimization and Asset Allocation with Alternative Investments. Asset Pricing and Risk Measurement.
- Forced Ranking 2003: Level 1 (top decile). PMM 2001: A2, PMM 2002: A1, PMM 2003: A1.
- http://www.ubs.com

BBVA

Quant Strategist & Trader of stock options 1998 - 2001 (3 years)

- Proprietary Trader at the Equity Relative Value Desk.
- Relative value models for various trading desks.
- Pricing, hedging and management of portfolios with financial derivatives, structured and synthetic products.
- http://www.bbva.es

Education

Harvard University

Postdoctoral Research Fellow at RCC, Mathematical Finance · (2010 - 2013)

Cornell University

Visiting Scholar, Market Microstructure · (2010 - 2012)

Universidad Complutense de Madrid

Ph.D., Mathematical Finance · (2009 - 2011)

Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia - U.N.E.D.

Ph.D., Financial Economics · (1998 - 2003)

Universidad de Santiago de Compostela

B.Sc., M.Sc., Econometrics and Quantitative Economics · (1993 - 1998)